sempo.org 2010-06-11

# Privacy Policy - SEMPO

The Search Engine Marketing Professional Organization (SEMPO) has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to privacy policy disclosure. The following discloses our information gathering and usage practices for the web site located at http://www.sempo.org. Our goal is to provide you with a personalized online experience that provides you with the information, resources, and services that are most relevant and helpful to you. This Privacy Statement has been written to describe the conditions under which this web site is being made available to you. The Privacy Statement discusses, among other things, how data obtained during your visit to this web site may be collected and used. We strongly recommend that you read the Privacy Statement carefully. By using this web site, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Statement. If you do not accept the terms of the Privacy Statement, you are directed to discontinue accessing or otherwise using the web site or any materials obtained from it. If you are dissatisfied with the web site, by all means contact us at info@sempo.org, but otherwise, your only recourse is to disconnect from this site and refrain from visiting the site in the future.

The process of maintaining a web site is an evolving one, and SEMPO may decide at some point in the future, without advance notice, to modify the terms of this Privacy Statement. Your use of the web site, or materials obtained from the web site, indicates your assent to the Privacy Statement at the time of such use. The effective Privacy Statement will be posted on the web site, and you should check upon every visit for any changes. 

**_Links To Other Web Sites_**

The SEMPO web site contains links to other sites. If you access those links, you will leave SEMPO's web site. SEMPO is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. SEMPO cannot represent that their policies and practices will be consistent with this Privacy Statement. For example, other web sites may collect or use personal information about you in a manner different from that described in this document. Therefore, you should use other web sites with caution, and you do so at your own risk. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any web site before submitting personal information. 

**_TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT_**

**_Non-Personal Information_**

Non-personal information is data about usage and service operation that is not directly associated with a specific personal identity. SEMPO may collect and analyze non-personal information to evaluate how visitors use the SEMPO web site. 

**_Aggregate Information_**

SEMPO may gather aggregate information, which refers to information your computer automatically provides to us and that cannot be tied back to you as a specific individual. Examples include referral data (the web sites you visited just before and just after our site), the pages viewed, time spent at our web site, and Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. For example, when you request a page from one of our sites, our servers log your IP address to create aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns and for purposes of system administration. 

**_Log Files_**

Every time you request or download a file from the web site, SEMPO may collect and store data provided by your web browser, such as your IP address, in a log file. SEMPO may use this data to help diagnose problems with our server and to analyze paths through our Web site. This data also provides broad demographic information about our audience which we use to improve the SEMPO web site (for example, how many international users do we have, how many users use version 4.0 of Netscape, etc). SEMPO also may use this information to analyze trends, administer the web site, track users' movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use or for other business purposes. 

**_Cookies_**

Our site may use a feature of your browser to set a "cookie" on your computer when you access our site. Cookies are small packets of information that a web site's computer stores on your computer. SEMPO's web site can then read the cookies whenever you visit our site. We may use cookies in a number of ways, such as to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site, to deliver content specific to your interests and to track the pages you've visited to learn how many unique visitors we have, and to aid in analyzing navigation paths through our site. These cookies allow us to use the information we collect to customize your SEMPO experience so that your visit to our site is as relevant and as valuable to you as possible. Cookie tracking identifies you by using a unique number; personal information such as name and address are only correlated with cookie information to allow us to manage member login sessions.

Other companies which place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign their cookies to you in a process that SEMPO does not control. However, cookies cannot be used to identify individuals, only machines, so these advertisers will not know who you are.

Most browser software can be set up to deal with cookies. You may modify your browser preference to provide you with choices relating to cookies. You have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, certain of the functions and conveniences of our web site may not work properly, and you may be unable to use those SEMPO services that require registration in order to participate, or you will have to re-register each time you visit our site. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. We do not link non-personal information from cookies to personally identifiable information without your permission. 

**_Web Beacons_**

SEMPO's web site also may use web beacons to collect non-personal information about your use of our web site and the web sites of selected sponsors and advertisers, your use of special promotions or newsletters, and other activities. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our web site and selected sponsors' sites; how many people open our emails; and for what purposes these actions are being taken. Our web beacons are not used to track your activity outside of our web site or those of our sponsors. SEMPO does not link non-personal information from web beacons to personally identifiable information without your permission. 

**_Personal Information_**

Personal information is information that is associated with your name or personal identity. SEMPO may use personal information to better understand your needs and interests and to provide you with better service. On some SEMPO web pages, you may be able to request information, subscribe to mailing lists, participate in online discussions, collaborate on documents, provide feedback, submit information into registries, register for events, apply for membership, or join working groups. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, address, phone number, e-mail address, user IDs, and passwords. 

**_Registration_**

Although sections of the web site may be viewed simply by visiting http://www.sempo.org, in order to access some Content and/or additional features offered at the web site, you may need to sign on as a guest or register as a member. Information you provide on the web site may be used to create a member profile. Registration may be necessary so that we can maintain your membership and contact you when necessary regarding your membership or organizational information and in order to ensure the quality of our services. The registration form may require you to choose a member name and password and to provide us with information such as your first and last names, email address, and mailing address. Some information may be shared with other SEMPO individual members and organizations. Member contact information may be provided to other members to encourage and facilitate collaboration, research, and the free exchange of information. Your information may be added to our mailing lists. From time to time, member information may be shared with our affiliated companies, event organizers and/or other organizations that may offer additional benefits to our users. By providing us with your personal information on the membership application, you expressly consent to our storing, processing and distributing your information for these purposes.  Also, by providing us with your personal information, you expressly grant us and all other persons or entities involved in the operations of web site and our affiliated companies the right to transmit, monitor, retrieve, store, and use your information in connection with the operation of the web site. If you do not wish to share your personally identifiable information, you may opt-out of sharing. See the _Choice/Opt-Out_ section below for details. 

We also collect member's financial information (such as credit card numbers) for processing credit cards during online membership enrollment. This information is passed to a 3rd party credit card processing agency for payment processing.

**_Company Information_**

Company information is information that is associated with the name and address of member organizations and may include data about usage and service operation. The primary representative of any SEMPO member organization may request usage reports to gauge the extent of their employees' involvement in consortium activities. You should be aware that information regarding your participation in technical committees or working groups, for example, may be made available to your company's primary representative and to SEMPO staff members. 

**_HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION_**

SEMPO may use non-personal data that is aggregated for reporting about our web site usability, performance, and effectiveness. It may be used to improve the experience, usability, and content of the site. 

When accessing the web site, your personal user information may be tracked in order to ensure authorized access. SEMPO may use personal information you provide (such as your e-mail address) from the registration form to send you newsletters and occasional information about our services, to personalize your web experience, or to investigate cases of suspected fraud or abuse. 

**_Information Sharing_**

SEMPO does not sell, rent, or lease any individual's personal information or lists of email addresses to unaffiliated third parties for marketing purposes, and we take commercially reasonable steps to maintain the security of this information. However, SEMPO reserves the right to supply any such information to affiliated third parties and to unaffiliated third parties in connection with a sale, merger, assignment, joint venture or other transfer or disposition of a portion or all of SEMPO's assets or stock (including, without limitation, in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings) in order to enable a third party to continue part or all of SEMPO's mission. We also reserve the right to release personal information to protect our systems or business, when we reasonably believe you to be in violation of our Terms and Conditions of Use or if we reasonably believe you to have initiated or participated in any illegal activity. In addition, please be aware that in certain circumstances, SEMPO may be obligated to release your personal information pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or other orders. 

In keeping with our mission statement, SEMPO may maintain publicly accessible archives for the majority of our activities. For example, posting an email to any our hosted mail lists or discussion forums, supplying content to the web site, registering for one of our public meetings may result in your email address or other personal information becoming a permanent part of the publicly accessible archives, even if you subsequently opt-out of sharing your personal information. 

If you are a registered member of SEMPO, you should be aware that some items of your personal information may be visible to other SEMPO members and to the public. The SEMPO member database may retain information about your name, e-mail address, company affiliation (if an organizational member), and such other personal address and identifying data as you choose to supply. That data may be generally visible to other SEMPO members and to the public. Your name, e-mail address, and other information you may supply also may be associated in SEMPO's publicly accessible records with various committees, working groups, and similar activities that you join, in various places, including: (i) the permanently-posted attendance and membership records of those activities; (ii) documents generated by the activity, which may be permanently archived; and, (iii) along with message content, in the permanent archives of SEMPO's e-mail lists, which also may be public. 

Please remember that any information (including personal information) that you disclose in public areas of our web site, such as forums, message boards, and news groups, becomes public information that others may collect, circulate, and use. Because we cannot and do not control the acts of others, you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose information about yourself or others in public forums such as these. 

Privacy laws vary from country to country, and your own country's privacy laws and regulations may be different than US law. If you are unsure whether this privacy statement is in conflict with applicable local rules, you should not submit your information. If you are located within the European Union, you should note that your information will be transferred to the United States, which is deemed by the European Union to have inadequate data protection. Individuals located in countries outside of the US who submit personal information do thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Statement and to its transfer to and/or storage in the US. 

**_Security_**

SEMPO makes commercially reasonable efforts to protect personal information by users of the web site, including using firewalls and other security measures on its servers. No server, however, is 100% secure, and you should take this into account when submitting personal or confidential information about yourself on any web site, including this one. SEMPO assumes no liability for the interception, alteration, or misuse of the information you provide. You alone are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your personal information. Please use care when accessing this web site and providing personal information.

**_Access to and Accuracy of Member Information_**

SEMPO is committed to keeping the personal information of our members accurate. All the information you have submitted to us can be verified and changed. In order to do this, please email us a request at info@sempo.org. We may provide members with online access to their own personal profiles, enabling them to update or delete information at any time. To protect our members' privacy and security, we also may take reasonable steps to verify identity, such as a user ID and password, before granting access to modify personal profile data. Certain areas of SEMPO's web site may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords or other personal identifiers; a password prompt is your indication that a members-only resource is being accessed. 

**_Choice/Opt-Out_**

From time to time SEMPO may email you electronic newsletters, announcements, surveys or other information. If you prefer not to receive any or all of these communications, you may opt out by following the directions provided within the electronic newsletters and announcements. Alternatively, you can provide us with your instructions in the following ways: 

  1. You can send email to info@sempo.org 
  2. You can send mail to the following postal address:

> _SEMPO  
>  401 Edgewater Place, Suite 600  
> Wakefield, MA 01880_

**_Contacting Us_**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this web site, you can:

  1. send an email to info@sempo.org or
  2. send mail to the following postal address:

> _SEMPO  
>  401 Edgewater Place, Suite 600  
> Wakefield, MA 01880_
